muscleforlife.com 2019-03-18

# PRIVACY POLICY - Muscle For Life

**1.   Introduction**

Thank you for visiting Muscle for Life.  If you have not already read and agreed to our Terms of Service, please do so now.  This Privacy Policy, like our Terms of Service, must be agreed to you by you in order to have our permission to use our Service.

 **2.   Definitions**

Throughout this document, we may use certain words or phrases, and it is important that you understand the meaning of them.  The following is a non-exhaustive list of definitions of words and phrases found in this document:

“Muscle for Life” refers to our company, known as “M4L, Inc.”; our Site; our Service; or a combination of all or some of the preceding definitions, depending on the context of the word;

“Service” refers to the services that we provide through our Site, including our blog, health and fitness-related books and other services, and the Site itself;

“Site” refers to our website, [www.muscleforlife.com](https://www.muscleforlife.com/);

“User” refers to anyone who accesses our Site or uses our Service, regardless of whether such access involves any remuneration to any party;

“You” refers to you, the person who is governed by this Privacy Policy.

 **3.   Information Collected**

Identifying Information

We collect certain personal information from you when you sign up to our Service that can be used to identify you, such as your name, e-mail address, mailing address, and other information we deem relevant.  Because we use a third party payment processor, Stripe, you will not be required to submit any credit card details to us.  The information we collect from you, to the extent that it is private, is disclosed only in accordance with our Terms of Service and/or this Privacy Policy.

Non-Identifying Information

Whenever you visit our Site, we may collect non-identifying information from you, such as your IP address, referring URL, browser, operating system, cookie information, and Internet Service Provider.  Without a subpoena, voluntary compliance on the part of your Internet Service Provider, or additional records from a third party, this information alone cannot usually be used to identify you.

 **4.   Use of Your Information**

We may use your information to:

  * Enhance or improve User experience, our Site, or our Service.
  * Process transactions.
  * Send e-mails about our Site or respond to inquiries.
  * Send our newsletter and other e-mail updates.
  * Send third party offers.
  * Perform any other function that we believe in good faith is necessary to protect the security or proper functioning of our Site or Service.

 **5.   Accessing, Editing, and Removing Your Information**

Users may in some cases be able to review and edit the personal information they have provided to us by logging into their account on the Site and editing their account.  Although most changes may occur immediately, information may still be stored in a web browser’s cache.  We take no responsibility for stored information in your cache, or in other devices that may store information, and disclaim all liability for such.  In addition, we may, from time to time, retain residual information about you in our backup and/or database.

 **6.   Cookies**

We use cookies to remember your preferences and track advertisements.  For these reasons, it is necessary that you enable cookies in your browser, and you hereby acknowledge that we have informed you of our use of cookies and that you consent to our use of cookies in relation to your computer system.  Please be advised that we also use third party cookies.

 **7.   Third Party Websites**

Muscle for Life may post links to third party websites on its Site.  These third party websites are not screened for privacy or security issues by Muscle for Life, and you release us from any liability for the conduct of these third party websites.

Please be aware that this Privacy Policy, and any other policies in place, in addition to any amendments, does not create rights enforceable by third parties or require disclosure of any personal information relating to members of the Service or Site.  Muscle for Life bears no responsibility for the information collected or used by any advertiser or third party website.  Please review the privacy policy and terms of service for each site you visit through third party links.

 **8.   Third Party Access to Your Information**

Although you are entering into an Agreement with Muscle for Life to disclose your information to us, we do use third party individuals and organizations to assist us, including contractors, web hosts, and others.

Throughout the course of our provision of our Service to you, we may delegate our authority to collect, access, use, and disseminate your information.  For example, our web host stores the information that you provide to us, and we may hire outside contractors to perform maintenance or assist us in securing our website.

It is therefore necessary that you grant the third parties we may use in the course of our business the same rights that you afford us under this Privacy Policy.  For this reason, you hereby agree that for every authorization which you grant to us in this Privacy Policy, you also grant to any third party that we may hire, contract, or otherwise retain the services of for the purpose of operating, maintaining, repairing, or otherwise improving or preserving our website or its underlying files or systems.  You agree not to hold us liable for the actions of any of these third parties, even if we would normally be held vicariously liable for their actions, and that you must take legal action against them directly should they commit any tort or other actionable wrong against you.

Without limiting the generality of the foregoing, you authorize us to share your information with:

  * bbPress forum
  * Mailchimp
  * Stripe
  * Woobox

 **9.   Release of Your Information for Legal Purposes**

At times it may become necessary, for legal purposes, to release your information in response to a request from a government agency or a private litigant.  You agree that we may disclose your information to a third party where we believe, in good faith, that it is desirable to do so for the purposes of a civil action, criminal investigation, or other legal matter.  In the event that we receive a subpoena affecting your privacy, we may elect to notify you to give you an opportunity to file a motion to quash the subpoena, or we may attempt to quash it ourselves, but we are not obligated to do either.  We may also proactively report you, and release your information to, third parties where we believe that it is prudent to do so for legal reasons, such as our belief that you have engaged in fraudulent activities.  You release us from any damages that may arise from or relate to the release of your information to a request from law enforcement agencies or private litigants.

 **10.   Commercial and Non-Commercial Communications**

By providing information to the Site that forms the basis of communication with you, such as contact information, you waive all rights to file complaints concerning unsolicited email from Muscle for Life since, by providing such information, you agree to receive communications from us other anyone else covered under this Privacy Policy.  However, you may unsubscribe from certain communications by notifying Muscle for Life that you no longer wish to receive solicitations or information and we will endeavor to remove you from the database.

 **11.   Security Measures**

We take certain measures to enhance the security of our Site and Service, including using SSL Certificates.   However, we make no representations as to the security or privacy of your information.  It is in our interest to keep our website secure, but we recommend that you use anti-virus software, firewalls, and other precautions to protect yourself from security threats.

 **12.   Your California Privacy Rights**

Muscle for Life permits residents of California to use its services.  Therefore, it is the intent of Muscle for Life to comply with the _California Business and Professions Code_ §§ 22575-22579.  If you are a California resident you may request certain information regarding our disclosure of personal information to any third parties for their direct marketing purposes.   Various provisions throughout this Privacy Policy address requirements of the Californian privacy statutes.  In summary, you must presume that we collect electronic information from all visitors.  You may contact us at [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#bad9d5d4cedbd9cefad7cfc9d9d6dfdcd5c8d6d3dcdf94d9d5d7) with any questions.

 **13.   Minors**

Individuals under 18 years of age are not allowed to use our paid services, and individuals under 13 years of age must not use our Service at all.  If you become aware of a User who is under the required age to use all or any portion of our Service, please notify us immediately at [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#10737f7e64717364507d6563737c75767f627c7976753e737f7d) and provide us with full details as to why you believe they are below that age and we will address the issue.  If you are a User who is reported in this manner, we may require you to provide suitable proof of age, such as a copy of government identification, in order to continue using our Site and/or Service.

 **14.   International Transfer**

Your information may be transferred to – and maintained on – computers located outside of your state, province, country or other governmental jurisdiction where the privacy laws may not be as protective as those in your jurisdiction.  If you are located outside the United States and choose to provide information to us, Muscle for Life transfers Personal Information to the United States and processes it there.  Your consent to this Privacy Policy followed by your submission of such information represents your agreement to that transfer.

 **15.   Amendments**

Like our Terms of Service, we may amend this Privacy Policy from time to time.  When we amend this Privacy Policy, we will place a note on our Site as to when this Privacy Policy was last modified.  You must read this page each time you access our Service, and if you do not agree to the current version, you must cease using our Service immediately.

Last Modified:  April 23, 2013
